<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech on Olivier Lespagnon</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/</link><description>Recent content in Tech on Olivier Lespagnon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS ECS vs EKS : choose the right one</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/aws-ecs-vs-eks/choose_the_right_container/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/aws-ecs-vs-eks/choose_the_right_container/</guid><description>Containers have become an essential part of modern software development and deployment practices. Containers enable developers to package and deploy applications and their dependencies in a self-contained unit, simplifying application management and scaling. Containers are lightweight, portable, and can be easily moved between environments, making them ideal for cloud-based applications.
Amazon Web Services (AWS), one of the leading cloud providers, provides a number of container services, including Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS) and Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS).</description></item><item><title>Choosing the right Linux distro</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/choosing-the-right-linux-distro/choosing_the_distro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/choosing-the-right-linux-distro/choosing_the_distro/</guid><description>In the world of Linux users, the distro choice is super important. Everywhere you go on Internet, when you see someone talking about his distro, you&amp;rsquo;ll feel like they&amp;rsquo;re talking about their wife or their religion. It is THAT serious. So you need to understand what a distro is, and what each one can offer you.
GUI vs Command Line For Linux beginners, the command line in the terminal app can be a bit intimidating.</description></item><item><title>How does AI work ?</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/under-the-ais-hood/ai_hood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/under-the-ais-hood/ai_hood/</guid><description>AI, which stands for Artificial Intelligence, is a branch of computer science that aims to develop machines capable of performing tasks that typically require human intelligence, such as speech recognition, decision-making, and visual perception. At its core, AI involves the use of algorithms, which are a set of instructions that guide a computer&amp;rsquo;s actions.
Machine Learning is a particular subfield of AI that uses algorithms to learn from data and improve performance on tasks over time.</description></item><item><title>NodeJS is broken</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/nodejs-is-broken/nodejs_is_broken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/nodejs-is-broken/nodejs_is_broken/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not here to only critisize NodeJS. In fact it is the framework we use at my work, and in a LOT of companies. It has served us well over the years in the browser, and after that, it has continued to help us on the server. Given the widespread knowledge of javascript, it&amp;rsquo;s understandable that many people also reach for it when implementing their backends.
CPU JavaScript&amp;rsquo;s main disadvantage on the server is its single-threaded nature, which makes it difficult to fully utilize all the cores available.</description></item><item><title>The future of AI</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/the-future-of-ai/the_future_of_ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tech/the-future-of-ai/the_future_of_ai/</guid><description>I predict that AI will advance so much in the coming years that what seems incredible now, will seem normal in the future.
I recently encountered ChatGPT and Midjourney, which both display amazing intelligence. It&amp;rsquo;s astonishing to interact with them and see how they process language and generate text that&amp;rsquo;s almost perfect. Midjourney can also create images beyond human imagination with remarkable speed and efficiency. However, this is just the beginning, and we can expect even more impressive advancements in the near future.</description></item></channel></rss>