<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Soft skill on Olivier Lespagnon</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/tags/soft-skill/</link><description>Recent content in Soft skill on Olivier Lespagnon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olivierlespagnon.com/tags/soft-skill/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to train when taking on a new position</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/soft-skills/learn-a-new-job/learn_for_a_new_position/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/soft-skills/learn-a-new-job/learn_for_a_new_position/</guid><description>In our career, when we change jobs, or companies, it is common not to master all the aspects of this new function. This is why it is necessary to keep in mind certain methods in order to best facilitate our training and the transition. When I became a devops I had to face these same difficulties and I decided to talk about the methods that helped me.
Agree to start from scratch When you take up your position, most of the time you actually know very little about it.</description></item><item><title>How to write a good blog post</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/soft-skills/how-to-write-a-good-post/writing_good_post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/soft-skills/how-to-write-a-good-post/writing_good_post/</guid><description>Writing a blog post can be a daunting task, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure where to start or how to make your content interesting to your readers. But with a little planning and creativity, anyone can write an engaging blog post that will capture their audience&amp;rsquo;s attention and keep them coming back for more. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll share some tips and strategies for writing a blog post that is both informative and entertaining.</description></item></channel></rss>