<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Réalisations techniques on Olivier Lespagnon</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/tags/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/</link><description>Recent content in Réalisations techniques on Olivier Lespagnon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olivierlespagnon.com/tags/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Gathering all your service accounts on AWS</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tutorials/gathering-all-service-accounts-in-aws/gathering_svc_python/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tutorials/gathering-all-service-accounts-in-aws/gathering_svc_python/</guid><description>Gathering all services account in an AWS account is an important task for any organization that uses Amazon Web Services (AWS). This task involves retrieving information about all the services that are being used in an AWS account and aggregating it into a single location for better management and monitoring. This can be especially useful for organizations that have multiple AWS accounts and want to centralize their management and monitoring.</description></item><item><title>How to create and manage your infrastructure using Terraform</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tutorials/how-to-manage-your-infrastructure-using-terraform/terraform_infra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tutorials/how-to-manage-your-infrastructure-using-terraform/terraform_infra/</guid><description>If in your company you have to manage resources on the cloud where you have surely already wondered how to maintain an architecture plan and ensure that it meets your specifications. what to do if one of your machines goes down, because your links are disconnected, or you need to quickly modify the characteristics of a VM or a server. the miracle solution exists and it&amp;rsquo;s called terraform point with terraform you will be able to use code to write the desired infrastructure regardless of the cloud provider and with a simple command create it terraform point will also detect changes and bring your infrastructure back to the desired status.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Kubernetes</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tutorials/introduction-to-kubernetes/get_started_with_k8s/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/tutorials/introduction-to-kubernetes/get_started_with_k8s/</guid><description>Kubernetes is an open-source container management system. It was designed to automate the deployment, scaling, and management of container-based applications.
Main concepts of Kubernetes Kubernetes is based on different concepts that together form a coherent system to carry any application.
Node Cluster Container Pod Deployment Service Node A node is a physical or virtual machine that is part of a Kubernetes cluster and performs cluster tasks. Each node has an agent software called kubelet, which monitors the state of containers on the node and keeps them running.</description></item><item><title>Create and host a static website using Github Actions and Hugo</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/create-and-host-a-static-website-using-github-actions/github_website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/create-and-host-a-static-website-using-github-actions/github_website/</guid><description>Creating a website can be a daunting task. You need to learn a language, then choose a framework. Study it and then you can create your website. Now you need to learn styling for it to not look bad. Then you have to learn how to host it to make it visible by everyone. For a beginner who&amp;rsquo;s just looking to create a simple website to have a web presence this can be a lot.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Dependency Track and monitor you apps</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/deploy-dependency-track/deploying-dependency-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/deploy-dependency-track/deploying-dependency-track/</guid><description>In software development, a dependency refers to a component or module of a program that another component or module depends on in order to function correctly. A dependency is often a library or a package that is used by a particular code component to provide additional functionality or to abstract away complex or repetitive logic.
For example, a web application might depend on a library such as jQuery or React in order to interact with the DOM and provide dynamic user interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a dynamic secret manager</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/hashicorp-vault/hashicorp_vault/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/hashicorp-vault/hashicorp_vault/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Can you pass me the credentials for AWS?&amp;rdquo; I arrived at LaJavaness in March as a Devops intern. It should be noted that I come from a specialized systems and networks training. So without cloud skills taught in class. But personally it&amp;rsquo;s a domain that always attracted me and after having trained myself as much as possible, here I am in the middle of it.
LaJavaness is a company that produces AI solutions in the French way.</description></item></channel></rss>