<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Réalisations technique on Olivier Lespagnon</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/</link><description>Recent content in Réalisations technique on Olivier Lespagnon</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create and host a static website using Github Actions and Hugo</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/create-and-host-a-static-website-using-github-actions/github_website/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/create-and-host-a-static-website-using-github-actions/github_website/</guid><description>Creating a website can be a daunting task. You need to learn a language, then choose a framework. Study it and then you can create your website. Now you need to learn styling for it to not look bad. Then you have to learn how to host it to make it visible by everyone. For a beginner who&amp;rsquo;s just looking to create a simple website to have a web presence this can be a lot.</description></item><item><title>Deploy Dependency Track and monitor you apps</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/deploy-dependency-track/deploying-dependency-track/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/deploy-dependency-track/deploying-dependency-track/</guid><description>In software development, a dependency refers to a component or module of a program that another component or module depends on in order to function correctly. A dependency is often a library or a package that is used by a particular code component to provide additional functionality or to abstract away complex or repetitive logic.
For example, a web application might depend on a library such as jQuery or React in order to interact with the DOM and provide dynamic user interfaces.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a dynamic secret manager</title><link>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/hashicorp-vault/hashicorp_vault/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://olivierlespagnon.com/posts/r%C3%A9alisations-techniques/hashicorp-vault/hashicorp_vault/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Can you pass me the credentials for AWS?&amp;rdquo; I arrived at LaJavaness in March as a Devops intern. It should be noted that I come from a specialized systems and networks training. So without cloud skills taught in class. But personally it&amp;rsquo;s a domain that always attracted me and after having trained myself as much as possible, here I am in the middle of it.
LaJavaness is a company that produces AI solutions in the French way.</description></item></channel></rss>